Contact

inamkhan133@yahoo.com

www.linkedin.com/in/inam-ullah-khan-59661466 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

HTML

CSS

C#

Languages

English

urdu

Certifications

Python for Data Science and Al IBM Certified Solution Developer -Integration Bus v10.0

Spring: Framework in Depth

Spring: Test-Driven Development

with JUnit

Honors-Awards

Employee of the Month
1st Position Speed Programming
Qualified to ICPC 2015 Regional
Final

Inam Ullah Khan

ESB | Certified IIB | Java/Java 8 | Spring Boot | Microservices Pakistan

Summary

Around five years of experience of building large scale enterprise application using Object Oriented design principles and patterns with Test Driven Development approach.

I also have hands on experience integrating heterogeneous systems communicating over different protocols like TCP/IP, MQ, SOAP, REST, File based Systems etc and industry wide standard messages like ISO-8583 (Financial).

Furthermore, learning something new everyday to increase my knowledge base like I used to do when I was a fresh graduate.

Experience

Nisum

Senior Software Engineer January 2021 - Present (1 year 3 months)

In my first year with Nisum, I have started from fixing bugs and developing small features. Now I am proposing and developing complex solutions.

Taking ownership and responsibility of a feature which is assign to me or which I took it by my will from proposing solution to development to writing unit and integration test cases to deployed in on production in a required deadline. Always try to follow coding best practices and try not to leave behind any quality checks.

Assisting team members in achieving their tasks.

Also do PRs.

Karachi University
Visiting Faculty
September 2021 - Present (7 months)
Department of Computer Science

Systems Limited 3 years 10 months

Senior Software Engineer January 2019 - December 2020 (2 years)

Software Enginer

January 2018 - December 2018 (1 year)

Implemented Financial and Non-Financial Transactions for multiple banks. Implemented Title Fetch, IBFT, Bill Enquiry, Utility Bill Payment etc by integrating front end application with core banking system(T24) and RDV middleware using ISO8583, RDZ8583, Pipe Delimited string message format. Implemented SAF mechanism for Advice messages to RDV for IBFT, Utility Bill Payment etc.

Implemented Reversal Transactions which also goes into SAF.

Hands on SQL queries. Worked on Oracle and sql server db.

Assist new resources in Learning IIB.

Visit client for technical requirement gathering and also for high level business understanding.

Created/Updated design document/deployment document.

Associate Software Engineer
March 2017 - December 2017 (10 months)

Working as a middleware developer of Enterprise Service Bus (IBM Integration Bus & IBM Websphere MQ) as a part of IBM practice within Systems Limited.

Build and manage large scale middleware systems in terms of Service Oriented Architecture (SOA) accompanied with Enterprise Application Integration (EAI) patterns.

Integrated TCP/IP, MQ, SOAP and REST Services based systems.

Transform Delimited Data Stream into T24 OFS Data Format through message modelling and ESQL.

Integrated TCP/IP based system by transforming TPS Phoenix-8583 into T24 ISO-8583.

Integrated IBM BPM with Microsoft AX Dynamics through Soap Web Services. Develop reusable libraries, parsers and caching modules using Java and ESQL.

Optimize the existing processes by applying proper refactoring and embracing code simplicity.

Implemented Global Cache using JAVA.

Ciphers Lab LLC
Freelance Developer and Developer

Page 2 of 3

October 2016 - February 2017 (5 months)

Angular 1 , Ionic 1, NodeJS, ExpressJS and MongoDB.

Education

University of Karachi Bachelor of Science (BS), Computer Science · (2013 - 2017)

Govt. Dehli College, Karachi. Inter, Pre-Engineering · (2010 - 2012)

St.Lawrences Boy's School, Karachi. Matric, Science · (1998 - 2010)